A control is a safeguard or countermeasure designed to preserve confidentiality,
integrity and availability of data.
We also discussed defense in depth as
an implementation of multiple technical controls.
Now we will look at a scenario that uses multiple controls across the spectrum
including physical technical and administrative controls.
Payroll is one area in nearly every organization that requires
multiple levels of controls to ensure money is not mishandled.
Most will agree that just a single control is too risky.
So multiple controls are often implemented
to prevent payroll personnel from creating a fictional
employee and processing a check for that employee.
A logical or technical control is to ensure that a person
who processes payroll is not able to create a new employee record
and process the check, print file,
a physical control that helps reinforce that technical
control is to ensure the actual paper,
media that checks are printed on is secured in a
place that is not accessible to the person processing payroll.
Both of these controls can further be
enforced by creating an administrative control or policy
that regularly audits the technical and
physical controls by reviewing new employees added
to the system and by logging and verifying the number on physical checks.
Small and medium businesses have a particular
challenge when it comes to technical controls as
they often do not have sufficient personnel to
separate the duties within the payroll system.
In this case,
it may become necessary to implement only physical and
logical controls that align with the business needs.